http://www.stsimons-southsea.org.uk/for-church-members/privacy-notice/

St Simons Church Southsea
HomeSundaysCommunitiesSunday SuppersBreakthruStreet PastorsMenChildrenYouthMid-weekWhat's onContact usFind usMessage usWeddings/Funerals /BaptismsReport a Safeguarding concernRoom HireWho's WhoDonate onlineSearchOpen ChurchFor Church MembersDocumentsNewslettersPrayer DiariesRotasSermonsHome GroupsPrivacy NoticeSafeguardingI'm new
For Church MembersDocumentsNewslettersPrayer DiariesRotasSermonsHome GroupsPrivacy Notice
Home > For Church Members
> Privacy Notice
Privacy Notice
We take our responsibilities to protect your privacy seriously and we meet all requirements of the law.
Our Privacy Notice below gives details.
Parochial Church Council of Saint Simon’s Southsea
DATA PRIVACY NOTICE
1.  Your personal data - what is it?
Personal data related to a living individual who can be identified from that data.  Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession.  The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the GDPR).
2.  Who are we?
The Parochial Church Council of St Simon’s Southsea is the data controller.  This means it decides how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.   The Data Protection Officer (May 2018) is Dr Hugh Mason.
3.   How do we process your personal data?
The Parochial Church Council of Saint Simon’s Southsea complies with its obligations under the GDPR by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining unnecessary or excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure; and by ensuring that appropriate measures are in place to protect personal data.
We use your personal data for the following purposes:
to enable us to provide voluntary services for the benefit of the public;
to administer membership and electoral roll records;
to fundraise and promote the interests of the church and its charities;
to manage our employees and volunteers;
to maintain our own accounts and record (including the processing of gift aid applications);
to inform you of news, events, activities and services running at St Simon’s and other churches with whom we have a formal mission partnership;
to share your contact details with the Portsmouth Diocesan Office so that they can inform you of news of the Diocese and of events, activities and services which will be occurring in the Diocese.
4.   What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?
You give explicit consent so that we can keep you informed about news, events, activities and services, and process your gift aid donations.
Processing of data is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection law, or a collective agreement.
Processing is carried out by a not-for-profit body with a religious aim provided:
the processing relates only to members or former members or those people who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes; and
there is no disclosure to a third party without consent being obtained.
5.   Sharing your personal data
Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the church in order to carry out a service to other church members or for purposes connected with the church.  We will only share your data with third parties outside the church with your consent.
6.   How long do we keep your personal data?
We keep data in accordance with the guidance set out in the guide “Keep or Bin: Care of Your Parish Records”, which is available on the Church of England website.[1]
Specifically, we retain electoral roll data while it is still current; gift aid declarations and associated paperwork for up to six years after the calender year to which they relate; and parish registers (baptisms, marriages and funerals) permanently.
7.   Your rights and your personal data
Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data:
the right to request a copy of the personal data which the Parochial Church Council of St Simon’s Southsea holds about you;
the right to request that the Parochial Church Council of Saint Simon’s, Southsea corrects any personal data which is found to be inaccurate or out of date;
the right to request that you personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for the Parochial Church Council of Saint Simon’s, Southsea to retain such data;
the right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time;
the right to request that the data controller provide the data subject with his/her personal data and, wherever possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller (this is known as the right to data portability);[2]
the right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;
the right to object to the processing of personal data;
the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.[3]
8.   Further processing
If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, we will provide you with a new notice explaining this use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions.   Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.
9.   Contact details
To exercise all relevant rights, queries or complaints please in the first instance contact the Parish Administrator or the Data Protection Officer through the Parish Office.
1st May 2018
1.     Details about retention periods can currently be found in the Record Management Guides located on the Church of England  website at:   https://www.churchofengland.org/more/libraries-and-archives/records-management-guides
2.    This only applies where processing is based on legitimate interests, the performance of a task in the public interest or exercise of official authority, direct marketing and processing for the purposes of scientific or historical research and statistics.
3.    You can contact the Information Commissioner’s Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email at https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/   or by post to the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF.
© Copyright St. Simon's Church, Southsea 2020
023 9282 9440
St. Simon's Church, Waverley Road, Southsea, PO5 2PW
Follow us on Facebook
This church website is powered by Church Edit
